5 Lussac Court Lake St. Louis, MO 63367 bill@allbusinesscomputerservices.com

H: (636) 625-1118 C: (314) 852-6074

CAREER SUMMARY

Senior-level Project Manager with progressively responsible experience in Information Technology Management, Operational Analysis and Control, and Management Information Systems. Possesses a well-rounded management background in the conception, design, development, and implementation of a full array of computer products and systems. A versatile communicator who has demonstrated excellent oral and written communication skills by delivering technical and business information to diverse audiences, from small senior management groups to large convention assemblies. Recognized for his ability to bridge the technical and business aspects of the organization as the technology changes and impacts core business values. An experienced healthcare business consultant, whose experiences over the past 12 years have been, predominantly, in the implementation or upgrade of TriZetto's Facets application, performing over ten separate implementations, upgrades, and/or conversions, including the implementation of the Facets application for 5 "Blues."

KEY COMPETENCIES

Health Plan Payor Operations Business Process Improvement Systems and Procedures Development Facets Technical Leadership Testing/Quality Assurance/Control Project Management Operational Analysis Planning/Organizing Change Management Guidance/Mentoring Information Technology Management SDLC Environment Management Personnel and Staff Development System Architecture Design Custom Software Development

SELECTED ACHIEVEMENTS

Refined business process flow for faster and less costly claims adjudication

As the Senior Project Manager for Noridian Healthcare Solutions (NHS), I was responsible for managing the implementation of a new claims processing subsystem that would increase speed, reduce the per transaction cost, and increase NHS's ability and flexibility to quickly address new client needs. NHS processed claims for CMS Jurisdictions E & F, Medicaid claims for Iowa Medicaid, and commercial claims for BCBSND and BCBSWY. Even though a common claims processing engine was used, separate process flows were defined to address the specific needs of each line of business and the commercial claims process flow required the additional approval of the BCBS Association. The solution required the coordinated efforts of two third party software vendors, multiple hardware vendors, and the matrixed management of team members from multiple internal departments.

Controlled the cost of delivery

On the Blue Shield of California Facets software implementation project, involving multiple teams, multiple tracks of development, and the integration of multiple sub-systems connecting to the main software application, I helped control the costs associated with implementing such a complex project and of this magnitude by controlling the number of environments created for development, testing, training, and staging and by coordinating the scheduled use of those environments. As the Environment Governance Manager, I met with up to 40 company departmental representatives, of the multiple teams and development tracts, to determine when an additional environment was needed/justified and what additional hardware and/or subsystems would be included in that environment when completed.

Developed a requirements gathering and cost-justification process

Qualitech Computer Centers needed a process that their business representatives could use to gather the business requirements of their potential clients and help them determine the size and complexability of their new computer system. I created a 37 page questionnaire and complimentary computer program that would allow their reps to gather the clients' business requirements and, upon entering their responses to those questions into the program, would use that information to determine the size of the computer system and the specific computer software that was needed. The program would further calculate the cost of the complete system, calculate the cost savings that could be realized once the system was implemented, and generate a 26 page "Management Blueprint" Business Proposal and Cost Justification document used to present the solution to the client. The document restated the requirements gathered, identified the business needs, cost, and cost savings of the proposed solution. This process was so successful in the field, that it became a valued and effective component of Qualitech's marketing strategy system.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

All Business Computer Services LLC, Lake St. Louis, MO

2005 - Present

Working with several HMO's, provided business and technical leadership that helped them to either migrate to or upgrade their existing TriZetto FACETS software application. Topping the list of organizations are five "Blues" (BCBS of Missouri, BCBS of Michigan, BCBS of Louisiana, BS of California, & BCBS of Western New York) and they are accompanied by regional and national organizations like United Healthcare, the Government Employees Health Association (GEHA), MED3OOO of Florida, ASP Healthcare of Maryland, OSF Health Plans of Peoria, and CareSource Indiana. Because of diverse background experiences, the skill set provided to these and other organizations included project management, infrastructure design, environment management, and custom SQL & software development across the full SDLC model. The excellence in technical leadership and superior consultation has resulted in several profound letters of recommendation.

GenPact/Jawood, Bingham Farms, MI

2013 - 2014

As the Senior Project Manager for a major project within the Noridian Healthcare Solution EPMO, was responsible for coordinating the replacement of their EDI Front-End application. This included project management, infrastructure design, process flow, environment management, executive-level reporting, and training coordination/scheduling. The new solution utilized a more robust and scalable system architecture which necessitated the deployment of a newly architected infrastructure into each of four environments defined within their SDLC model and the coordination of efforts and collaboration with two 3rd party software vendors. Business and technical leadership was required to identify the many connection points within the process flow so that the implementation would allow the smooth transition from the old system to the new. Additionally, as the Provider Portal Project Manager, used the Agile methodology to manage, track, and report the progress of the two-week sprints used to complete its development.

Lanier & Associates, Atlanta, GA -- Senior Consultant

2003 - 2005

Technical Lead at TriZetto's Denver Hosting Center - multiple projects. In the first of four projects, led the development of a suite of programs that merged the contents of two FACETS databases into one, maintaining full referential integrity in the process. In a second project, led the development of a an automated EC Gateway Script Duplication sub-system that reduced the development time of HIPAA Gateway Scripts from 5 days to 5 hours. In a third project, automated the creation of UNIX Korn shell scripts that created reports and transmitted them via ftp to a remote client site, again allowing TriZetto to realize the benefit of significantly reduced development time. In the fourth project, automated the conversion of raw data into fully relational data that allowed it to be quickly inserted into a FACETS database, thereby saving hundreds of hours that would have been spent performing the same task manually.

Partec, Inc., St. Louis, MO -- Senior Consultant

2000 - 2002

Held numerous positions within multiple companies on multiple projects. As the Chief Technology Officer for CoForce.com, managed a cross-functional group and led the reorganization of the software development team by implementing standard full life cycle development processes, including complete change management, system and user testing, Quality Assurance, and code migration procedures. As the Project Manager and Database Architect of the OnTrack 2000 Project for Computer Sales International, developed a complete project plan for the development of an n-tier, web-based application that included the training, development, rollout, and support of that product. Also helped manage the eight in-house and four vendor team members. As the UNIX Technical Lead and Object Developer for Blue Cross Blue Shield of Missouri, simultaneously led the technical effort on two project teams and contributed to a third, created a common code library, managed a team of five Unix Developers, and coordinated seven additional developers to standardize the error reporting and program log reporting systems. Helped lead a cross-functional team of five to develop a Windows-based Intranet and Internet application for distributing files to external resources.

All Business Computer Services, Inc., Lake St. Louis, MO -- Senior Consultant

1989 - 2000

Provided technical leadership for client organizations on multiple projects, serving national companies such as Ralston Purina, CitiCorp, Bridge Communications, and May Co., as well as regional and local companies. Was also involved in the design and development of automated systems used by these organizations.

Plus Five Computer Software, St. Louis, MO – Divisional Vice President

1988 - 1989

Managed the development of a new product, "Voxel 4-D", a real-time 3D image rendering system for the display of medical CAT-Scan and MRI data on 50 different UNIX platforms. Also developed a multi-windowed demo of the mainstream product, UNIX MUMPS.

EDUCATION

- M.S. Full-Cycle Computer Software Development, School of Hard Knocks ©, St. Louis, MO
- B.S. Business Administration/Management Information Systems, Southern Illinois University

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

Technical expertise includes, but is not limited to, the following:

OPERATING SYSTEMS:

• Windows NT / 95 / 98 / 2000 / 2003 / 2008 / XP / Vista / 7 / 8, UNIX, AIX, HP/UX, LINUX

LANGUAGES:

• C, C++, C#, Visual Basic, VBA, VB Script, Java, JavaScript, JSP, JSON, JQuery, Windows Script, PowerShell, UNIX Shell Script (sh, ksh, csh), PERL, HTML/HTML5, Razor CSHTML, CSS/CSS3, ASP.NET, ADO.NET, MVC, XSLT, XML, XAML, Silverlight (3-5), Entity Framework, Angular.js, Bootstrap.js, node.js

DATABASES:

• Sybase (11.x, 12.x, 15.x), Oracle (7.x, 8i, 9, 11), MS SQL Server (6.5, 7.0, 2005, 2008, 2010, 2012), Informix, DB2/2, ERwin DB Modeling (3.5.2), Power Designer 10.0

Tools:

MS Office (2003-2013), MS Project, MS Visio, SharePoint, TFS, Visual Studio (6-2013), Expression Blend (3-4), InfoPath, TFS, SourceSafe, PVCS, sccs, git, Jira, Apache Ant, npm, grunt, bower, yeoman, Karma, Protractor, Subversion, Eclipse, WebSphere, MS IE, Netscape Navigator, Google Chrome, Firefox, EC Gateway, SSIS, SSMS, SSRS, Crystal Reports, Business Objects, Data Integrator, Brio, HPXR, Clarity

OTHER DISCIPLINES:

• EDI, X12, ETL, Data Mart, Data Warehouse, n-tier App Dev, TriZetto/Erisco FACETS versions 2.94-5.01, Broadband RF, Bar Code Labeling

HEALTHCARE EXPERIENCES

Alphabetical List

APS Healthcare

Blue Cross Blue Shield of Louisiana

Blue Cross Blue Shield of Michigan

Blue Cross Blue Shield of Missouri

Blue Cross Blue Shield of Nebraska

Blue Cross Blue Shield of New Jersey

Blue Cross Blue Shield of North Dakota

Blue Cross Blue Shield of Western New York

Blue Cross Blue Shield of Wyoming

Blue Shield of California

Caresource Indiana

Express Scripts, Inc.

Government Employees Health Association

MED3OOO

Noridian Healthcare Solutions

OSF HealthPlans

Trizetto Hosting Center in Denver, CO

United Health Care of Colorado

Western & Southern Financial Life